hey everybody welcome back to the three
question Series where we hear from women
all across the PCA about what God is
doing in their little corner and today
we have with us one of my favorite
people Joy beans and yes I said beans
like pinto beans here she is Joy beans
good morning Joy good morning how are
you I am doing well I'm so glad you're
here Joy is joining us as you can see
she is representing our UF
Baltimore will you please tell us are
you married I am married um my husband
trip and I have been married we have
been married 25 years in November ah
which is crazy um yes so we have and
trip is the campus minister at with Ruf
at University of Maryland Baltimore
County
UMBC um and I am on campus staff there
and we have three
children we practice I we were talking
the other day and trip said yeah we have
three kids two are married and one just
graduated high school and I was like
that feels really strange to say two of
my kids are married but they are but
they are but they are our son Luke got
married in the fall added Lindsay to our
family our daughter adelyn got married
two weeks ago added Steven to our family
and our daughter
Ka um just graduated to high school two
days ago and she'll be headed off to
school in the fall Joy Of course as you
can tell does not look old enough to
have these children but she does and
she's gonna answer our three questions
the first of which she started to tell
us about your little corner of the
kingdom is R youf tell tell us again
where because most people don't know all
the designated areas that's great Ruf uh
reformed University fellowship at
University of Maryland Baltimore County
and you are what kind of staff so I am
campus staff there um I actually work
part-time campus staff like I said uh my
husband is the campus Minister there and
I came on staff nine years ago um Ruf
has this great thing where uh they found
that women who happen to be married to
campus ministers were also really called
to love college students and spend time
with them and this um afforded our
family a way to minister together uh
without me having to have a another side
hustle somewhere else
right because you were already doing it
I was already doing it one of the
greatest gifts God's ever given our
family is that um I've always felt
separately called sometimes before a
trip uh to the Ministries that that God
is calling trip to um he was in Youth
Ministry for 17 years um and then I at a
church um I started heading up a Col a
college Ministry there and that's how we
kind of got into Ruf from there
so so you've been doing this a long time
and I would love to hear just if you
could tell us one story maybe recently
maybe not that of something God has done
through this ministry that you have yeah
for sure um so yeah we've been on in
June well I guess June 1st has come and
gone um this is our 12th year in Ruf
like I said I think I've been on staff
about nine of them um and yeah both most
of what I do is one-on ones it's really
that is that is my great joy of doing
Ministry um with these with the college
students and so I meet with most of the
most of the female students um most of
the young women on campus that are in
our ministry um
and I have a a great story of a student
she actually just graduated and um
I she came in as a transfer um and I
started meeting with her I guess we met
three years for the time that she was at
UMBC she kind of came into Ruf through
the best possible way um her friend was
coming to Ruf was a Believer and um she
wasn't but she was
having kind of some Conflict at home and
um her friend who I was already having
one-on ones with said hey you wanna you
want to come meet with joy and she said
sure I I guess like I think that's kind
of you know it's kind of weird to if
you're if you grow up outside of a
church um yeah adults don't pay a lot of
attention to you right and so we find
that with a lot of college students
they're like I don't know why I'm here
having a cup of coffee with you but okay
um so she and I started meeting uh she
was having a lot of conflict with her
family we just kind of started talking
about it you know I'm really clear like
where my perspective is you don't have
to love Jesus to meet with me or come to
Ruf at all um but that's where you
know he's always there when we're
talking so um we just started kind of
having conversations
and I I wanted to to kind of introduce
the idea of Faith she was she's very
unfamiliar with the Bible when she first
started she had the sweetest question
for me she she came and she said listen
because she's a very performance
oriented um you know D1 athlete and she
said how much of the Bible do you need
to have read before you can consider
Christianity she's like
85% oh and I said that is like it was
such a great question um yeah and and so
we talked about a thief on a cross he
was one of the students that um when we
opened up the Bible in small group it
was like Hey we're on page
482 uh super subtle everybody had the
same Bibles um and she just kept coming
back and in in our 101 she was like I
just kind of inquired I was like hey
what kind of made you enter the Ruf
world you know like actually come to
small group actually come to large group
and and she said you know I've been a
lot of places and I've met a lot of
people but um I immediately felt cared
for in R
Us um and so Flash
Forward last year I'm getting her ready
to go home because she is thinking about
faith and she's she told me I know when
I go home she's getting ready to go home
for
Christmas she said I know when I go
home um and my parents find out I've
been going to a Bible study they're
gonna think I'm a
fool and I just need I need to I need to
practice what I'm gonna say about it and
um and so we just kind of talked about
it and and how to how have her Express
that this has become important to her
though she did not claim Faith she was
just she just wanted to kind of hang out
with this group of people who she knew
loved Jesus but that her parents would
discount yeah um and you know so she
comes home she comes back this fall I
kind of
pitched but the beginning of their
senior year um if I've been meeting with
a student regularly I kind of try to lay
out their senior year with like what
we're going to do in a one-on-one what
do they want to learn it could be simple
it could be complex it's been all over
the map like how do I open up a checking
account to yeah you know what is you
know what is the Theology of something
or other and yeah you know we just kind
of work through it the whole year make
sure that they they get the answers to
questions they've been having before
they leave campus and and so I just kind
of pitched I was like hey you know what
are you thinking what have you been
thinking about faith now that you've
been home for the summer and we're
coming back and and she goes oh she goes
I uh I became a Christian last
spring catch up Joy I know I know and it
was it was such a sweetness and and to
be honest with you um that's that's how
that's how God seems to work um in in
the ministry that that we've been
involved in it's in it's really subtle
we don't have like the you know dramatic
conversions it's these simple
conversations and and these kind of like
oh God just kind
of
beautifully and
sweetly enters them into the kingdom and
without much fanfare at all and it's
it's just a sweetness it's just a change
in what he's done in their hearts and
then we get to kind of discover along
with them what he's been doing um she's
going to school oh yeah it's it's the
most beautiful thing I get to do I'm
getting like I love this I love this
student I'm tearing up um yeah she's
going to grad school and she asked me uh
hey can you help me find a church and um
one of the beautiful things about is
that we have a network across the
country kind of across the world right
and um and we we're helping her get
connected so it's
exciting it's what we hope for right
it's totally what we hope for so how how
can we like we the PCA your brothers and
sisters in what you're doing how can we
encourage and support you in your sort
of like everyday life wow um man just
pray keep praying the the universe you
know the University campus right now has
all sorts of things happening all sorts
of
um clashes and a lot of beauty too um
and and we absolutely I love that use
the word privilege it's absolutely um my
privilege to be able to be sent in kind
of the forward- facing Ministry of Ruf
um but prayer uh is is super important
um I'm I'm going to be really honest
here uh if there's a if there's
a college that you love if there's a
Collegiate Ministry person that you love
please support them
financially please sign up for our
newsletters um the
more the more um we can be forward-
facing and spend time with students and
the less we have to kind of scramble
around for for
funding
uh the more the more we get to just go
do what we love to do most um yeah there
there's a great Beauty to fundraising uh
I never thought that I would say that
when we first
start and anyone who fundraises is like
are you short no but there there is a
great Beauty to the faith of fundraising
and I I'm not complaining about that at
all like I love I can tell you a
thousand stories of the way that the
Lord has been so kind to um trip and I
in our fundraising um but uh but the
less we have to think about that so you
know focus on that so much the more time
we get to kind of just be with students
and really walk alongside them um so if
you if you love a campus if you love a
campus Minister a campus staff please
support them um if you don't have one
that you love you
MBC now you
do thank you Joy for giving us some time
I really appreciate it my pleasure thank
you so much for having me